Rubiyet Fardous

Software Engineer

+880 1862 297 140 rubiyetfardous@gmail.com

tubiyet.me 🕠 github.com/rubiyet

Dhaka, Bangladesh in linkedin.com/in/rubiyetfardous

About Me

A Software Engineer with deep knowledge of modern web and mobile app technologies capable of designing and implementing visually pleasing, efficient, and optimized software. Experienced in delivering quality products in production environments following proper design principles and methodologies.

Work Experience

Software Engineer

TechnoNext Ltd. (US-Bangla Group)

TechnoNext excels in providing comprehensive IT solutions with innovative services spanning web design, development, ERPs, CRMs, e-commerce, IoT, AI, and more.

Dec 2023 to Present | Full-Time

- Developed landing web apps, user interfaces, and admin dashboards for diverse B2B/B2C sectors such as online travel, food delivery, healthcare, and e-commerce.
- Technologies utilized: React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Ant Design, Chakra UI, DaisyUI, Zustand, REST API, WebSocket, NextAuth.js, SWR, React Form Hook, Yup, CI/CD, Docker.

Software Engineer

Arbree Limited

Tailored Software Consulting for Efficient Solutions

Mar 2023 to Nov 2023 (9 months) | Full-Time

- Developed frontend solutions for client Admin Dashboards and Landing pages.
- Technologies utilized: React (Next.js), Vue.js (Nuxt.js), PHP, Laravel, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Redux, REST API, Vercel Hosting, Git Version Control.
- Contributed to Mobile App development using React Native.
- Utilized Figma for design processes.

Junior Software Engineer

HelloTask Pte. Ltd.

An app-based platform for hiring domestic workers and working on connecting digital billboards to a centralized network.

Jan 2021 to Jan 2023 (2 years 1 month) | Full-Time

- Designed, developed, and maintained the Administrative Interface, Management Console's Panel, CRM and Landing pages
- Technologies utilized: React (Next.js), Vue.js, Bootstrap 5, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, REST API, Amazon S3, Vercel Hosting, GitHub Pages, Git Version Control.
- Collaborated with designers using Figma for the design process.

Education

BSc. in CSE

American International University-Bangladesh | Year: 2018 - 2022 | CGPA: 3.32

Publication

Applying Scrum Development on Safety Critical Systems | DOI: 10.5815/ijitcs.2022.05.04

Tech Stack

Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, PHP, Python, C/C++, JAVA, C#, SQL

Frameworks

React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Vue.js, Bulma, React Native, Nest.js, Laravel, Blade

Protocol, Tools & Others

Material UI, Ant Design, DaisyUI, Chakra UI, Redux, Zustand, Apollo GraphQL, REST API, WebSocket, NextAuth.js, SWR, React Query, Storybook, React Form Hook, Formik, Yup, Jest, WordPress, Firebase, Nginx, CI/CD, Docker, Postman, insomnia, Vercel, Git, Jira, Linux.

Projects

UNFPA

The United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) delivers a world where every pregnancy is wanted, every birth is safe, and every young person's potential is fulfilled.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Vercel Hosting.
- Github: https://unfpa.vercel.app

University of Asia Pacific

The University of Asia Pacific's dynamic landing website offers engaging and interactive content to visitors.

- Vue.js (Nuxt.js), PHP, Laravel, Bootstrap, CSS, Sass, Redux, Vercel Hosting
- Demo Live on: https://uap-console.vercel.app

EFDMS

The National Board of Revenue (NBR) aims to modernize and streamline fiscal monitoring and reporting through electronic devices.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Redux, React Query, React Modal, Firebase, Vercel Hosting.
- Demo Live on: https://efdms.vercel.app

Solaric

Solaric is a group of renewable energy development companies.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Vercel Hosting, Figma
- Design: https://www.figma.com/file/MdqsE3xRFVxtSsj3cLqcqQ/Solaric-Monitoring-Dashboard
- Demo Live on: http://119.148.39.219:3000

Kanban board

Kanban board web application for visual project management and task tracking.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Vercel Hosting
- Demo Live on: https://kanbanboard-console.vercel.app

Custom Captcha

Custom captcha system for improved security and user experience.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, React webcam, Lottie, Vercel Hosting
- Demo Live on: https://customcaptcha.vercel.app

Exabyting

Digital transformation solutions will lead your business to success.

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Vercel Hosting, Figma
- Demo Live on: https://exabyting-console.vercel.app